# Patrick Dugan

www.dailydoog.com dugan.pat@gmail.com 716.481.5567

# Experience

# **Product Designer, Nextdoor Inc.**

June 2014 to Present :: San Francisco, CA

I currently work at Nextdoor in the role of Product Designer. I joined Nextdoor in June of 2014 as a member of the Designer Fund Bridge program. Nextdoor is a private social network for you, your neighbors, and your community.

# Technical Strategist, Google Inc.

March 2011 to August 2013:: Mountain View, CA

I worked as a member of the Google Wallet team in an internal development capacity. In this role I helped create models that proactively identified fraud occurring across Google's payment platforms. I additionally worked as an interaction designer within Google Research and as a member of the Google Transparency Reporting team.

# Technical Development Program, Liberty Mutual Insurance Group

May 2010 to March 2011:: Boston, MA

I participated in the Liberty Mutual Technical Development program and was a member of the company's first mobile development team. In this role I helped design and build Liberty's first Android, iOS, and mobile-web based applications. Additionally, I conducted user research across a number of Liberty's consumer facing mobile and desktop based applications.

# Systems Analyst [Intern], Polaris Global Mobility Software

March 2010 to May 2011 :: Bellevue, WA

I tested and filed bugs against custom integrations of an expatriate employee payroll management solution. Additionally, I provided technical assistance and support for Fortune 500 clients that included Thomson Reuters, Johnson & Johnson, and Goldman Sachs. I also lead a project to develop an internal collaborative knowledge-sharing repository.

# Education

Graduate

# **University of Washington**

2013 to 2014 :: Seattle, WA

Master of Science; Human Computer Interaction (In progress); GPA: 3.89

# Undergraduate

# **University of Washington**

2008 to 2010 :: Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Arts; Information Systems; GPA: 3.54

## Individual Study

### College of San Mateo

2011 to 2013 :: San Mateo, CA

Computer Science (Individual Study); GPA: 4.0

### San Francisco Academy of Art University

2012 to 2013 :: San Francisco, CA

Web Design & New Media (Individual Study); GPA: 3.8

# Frontend & Markup

CSS Jinja2 jQuery HTML5 Rich-Snippets

#### **Tools**

Sketch Illustrator Balsamiq Framer.js Fireworks Photoshop

#### **Databases**

mySQL Google Cloud SQL

#### Languages

Java Python Javascript

#### **IDEs**

Coda Android Studio

# Frameworks

Android App Engine

#### Design

Heuristic Evaluation Cognitive Walkthrough Low & Hi-Fi Prototyping

#### Research

Card Sorting Task Analysis Contextual Inquiry Think-Aloud Protocol Eye-Tracking Analysis

#### **About Me**

I enjoy creating elegant, useful and usable user-experiences

I love hiking, camping, running and generally anything that involves being outdoors

I have also maintained a personal blog since early 2011

Patrick Dugan Resume :: 1 of 2

www.dailydoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567

# Selected Projects

# **Liberty Mutual Mobile Channel Development**

October 2011 to March 2012:: Liberty Mutual Insurance:: Boston, MA

- Developed technical business requirements for Liberty Mutual's first iOS, Android, & mobile-web applications
- · Assisted in execution of multiple mobile usability studies and mobile heuristic evaluations
- · Created low & high-fidelity wireframes, user storyboards, and XML android activity layouts

# **USMC ProFitness Android Application**

February 2012 :: Freelance :: Berkeley, CA

- · Designed, developed, and published an android fitness tracking application
- Drove 10,000+ unique application installs with backwards compatibility through Android 2.2 (Froyo)
- · Conducted multiple usabilty studies with active duty marines leading to implementation of actionable improvements

# Google Event Connect Redesign

October 2012 to August 2013 :: Google, Mountain View, CA

- Drafted and prototyped improved visual redesign for major components of an internal event planning application
- Built functional HTML/CSS/Javascript prototypes for use by relevant stakeholder groups within Google Research
- · Consolidated information architecture while also improving event creation, discovery, and logistics management user-flows

# Additional Experience

# **UW Electrical Engineering Research Assistant**

January 2013 to June 2014 :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

# UW Laboratory for Usability, Testing, and Evaluation (LUTE) Research Assistant

September 2013 to December 2013:: University of Washington:: Seattle, WA

# **Undergraduate Research Learning Community Mentor**

September 2013 to January 2014 :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

# Google Transparency Report Design Lead

April 2013 to August 2013 :: Google :: Mountain View, CA

# Google Event Connect Design Lead

October 2012 to August 2013 :: Google :: Mountain View, CA

# **Liberty Mutual Technical Development Program Inductee**

June 2010 :: Liberty Mutual :: Boston, MA

# University of Washington Foster Information Systems Mentorship Program

September 2009 to June 2010 :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

### University of Washington Resident Adviser

September 2009 to June 2010 :: University of Washington HFS :: Seattle, WA

### **United States Marine Corps Officer Candidate**

June 2009 to September 2009 :: USMC Officer Candidate School :: Quantico, VA

# BuffaloGreenArt.com Web Developer (Intern)

May 2008 to September 2008 :: Buffalo Green Art :: Buffalo, NY

# **Boy Scouts of America; Eagle Scout**

March 2005 :: Boy Scouts of America :: Buffalo, NY

Patrick Dugan Resume :: 2 of 2 www.dailydoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567